<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Chris Albon</title>
    <link>https://chrisalbon.com/notes/index.xml</link>
    <description></description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://chrisalbon.com/notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Model Cards</title>
      <link>https://chrisalbon.com/notes/ethical_machine_learning/model_cards/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisalbon.com/notes/ethical_machine_learning/model_cards/</guid>
      <description>Models are are proposed in a 2019 paper by the then Google team. The basic idea, as proposed. Is to create a</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I Said To My Team During COVID-19</title>
      <link>https://chrisalbon.com/notes/technical_management/what_i_said_to_my_team_during_covid-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisalbon.com/notes/technical_management/what_i_said_to_my_team_during_covid-19/</guid>
      <description>Hey all. With everything that is going on, I want to be explicit with you all about how we work in this new reality.
 All this is not normal. This is not a regular work week but from home, this is something harder. We are still learning how to operate in this new reality, we will make mistakes at the start, and we will get better at it in time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I Learned Tracking My Time At Techstars</title>
      <link>https://chrisalbon.com/notes/personal/what_i_learned_from_tracking_my_time_at_techstars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 11:53:49 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisalbon.com/notes/personal/what_i_learned_from_tracking_my_time_at_techstars/</guid>
      <description>In the fall of 2015, New Knowledge, a company I cofounded with two friends was offered a slot in the 2016 class of Techstars Cloud. Like most people in tech, I had heard about Techstars, but in truth I barely knew anything specific, particularly about the day-to-day of the program. Was Techstars a permanent hackathon fueled by Soylent and Adderall? Was it three months of guest speakers and sponsored happy hours?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Health System Destruction During The Mozambican Civil War</title>
      <link>https://chrisalbon.com/notes/social_good/health_system_destruction_renamo_mozambique/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2011 11:53:49 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisalbon.com/notes/social_good/health_system_destruction_renamo_mozambique/</guid>
      <description>Mozambique’s political history has been shaped by its geography. Stretched from north to south along more than 1,500 miles of coastline, the territory was first colonized by the Portuguese, who established a series of trading ports. Through these ports the colonists extracted the agricultural and commercial wealth of the territory. Under Portuguese rule, the health system in Mozambique centered on the needs of the European settler community and their economic interests.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Health System Reconstruction In Post-War Kosovo</title>
      <link>https://chrisalbon.com/notes/social_good/health_system_reconstruction_post_war_kosovo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2011 11:53:49 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisalbon.com/notes/social_good/health_system_reconstruction_post_war_kosovo/</guid>
      <description>In 1963, Kosovo became an autonomous province of Serbia in Yugoslavia under Josip Tito. Long before then, friction had existed between the ethnically Albanian and Serbian communities living inside and around Kosovo. These tensions escalated in the 1980s as ethnic Albanians pushed for greater autonomy for Kosovo and stronger connections to neighboring Albania, while Serbians wanted to maintain strong ties with Belgrade.
Since World War II, Yugoslavia’s (and therefore Kosovo’s) health system was based on the Semashko model common in other Communist states: centralized decision making, large institutions, and the domination of hospital, curative, and specialist care (Parmelee 1985; Shuey et al.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Problem Of Rebel Mobilization</title>
      <link>https://chrisalbon.com/notes/social_good/puzzle_of_rebel_mobilization/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2011 11:53:49 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisalbon.com/notes/social_good/puzzle_of_rebel_mobilization/</guid>
      <description>The Puzzle When looking at the destruction of health systems in civil wars, we are presented with an empirical puzzle: why do some civil wars see widespread destruction to health systems and other civil wars see far less?
During Mozambique’s civil war, RENAMO’s campaign against the government health system caused more than two million people to lose access to health care (Cliff and Noormahomed 1993). In Colombia’s civil war, FARC fighters often targeted stocks of drugs destined for the civilian population (Beyrer et al.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Structure Of Health Systems</title>
      <link>https://chrisalbon.com/notes/social_good/health_systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2011 11:53:49 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisalbon.com/notes/social_good/health_systems/</guid>
      <description>While health systems vary in the role of the private sector, the priority given to primary and specialized care, the level of access enjoyed by citizens, and a host of other characteristics, most health systems (particularly in less developed states) share a basic structure based on a hierarchical organization of health care provision. Most citizens’ primary point of contact with health systems is usually through health posts, health clinics, and health centers.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>